Nzeakor Emmanuel

► +2348118353243☑ emmanuelnzeakor00@yahoo.com

Full Stack Web Developer

Summary

An experienced full stack developer with 3+ years in the industry and high-level proficiency in the following: Web Development, Java and App-development etc. I am very familiar and experienced with Web and Mobile Application Architecture and have worked with a good number of successful development teams.

Core Competencies

- Excellent Instincts
- Research based decision
- Meticulous reviewer
- Independent Thinker
- Collaborative Team Player
- Data and statistical analysis

- Project
 Management
- Time Management
- Interpersonal Relationship
- Persuasive
 Communicator
- Creative

Skills

Databases: Mongo DB, Firebase

Languages/Frameworks: VB.Net, HTML5,CSS3, Bootstrap, Vanilla Js, React js,

Node js, Express js. Vue, NextJs, Java, React-Native

Applications: Git, GitHub, Code sandbox, Word press, Wix

Server Side: Php

Other Applications: Microsoft Office, Photoshop

Work Experience

Web Developer (Contract)

Dec 2020- Current

Geria | UK -Nottingham

- Designing and building the website front-end.
- Creating the website architecture.
- Designing and managing the website back-end using crm plugin.
- Conducting website performance tests using Pingdom and Google PageSpeed Insights.
- Troubleshooting content issues.

Full Stack Web Developer (Part – Time)

Aug 2020- Current

Devttech | UK - Kent

- Designed, architected and built the company's website using Vue is and firebase
- Modernized some application built on older framework to React.JS
- Built and designed full stack applications in which the frontend is hosted on firebase and backend is hosted on heroku which was being built with MongoDb
- Designed, architected and wrote the front-end for a client ecommerce application using ReactJS with more than 10 reusable components with payment integration using stripe

Data Scientist FEB 2018- JAN 2019

SDSD PRESTIGE | Nigeria

DATA SCIENTIST

- Collection, Analyzing, Entering and Processing of Data for Vessels
- Verification of Data before it's been delivered to Clients
- Review data for deficiencies or errors, correct any incompatibilities if possible and check output
- Research and obtain further information for incomplete documents
- Apply data program techniques and procedures

V-CHARTERING

V Chartering Dry and Wet is the perfect tool for brokers looking for a quick and powerful yet cost effective tool. Designed to eliminate time consuming manual processes, the software matches cargo and vessels quickly

 Creation of Thomas Stowage V- Charter file differentiating between dry and wet Items and assigning their respective Stowage Factor(s)

TEXT ANALYSIS

Text analysis software, also called text analytics or text mining software, helps users gain insights from both structured and unstructured text data using natural language processing (NLP). Such insights include sentiment analysis, key phrases, language, themes and patterns, and entities, among others.

- Create structured data out of free text content.
- Using machine learning to train shipping models (NER).

IT Instructor and Trainer

Sept 2016 – Mar 2017

CHS COMPUTER INSTITUTE | Nigeria

- Instructed and trained attendees in a variety of subjects and matters.
- Developed training materials and presentations.
- Train and Instruct student on how to use several computer software and develop website

Education

Bachelor's Degree (B.Sc) Computer Science and Informatics	2018 – current
Federal University Otuoke, Bayelsa state	
National Diploma, Computer Science	2015 - 2017
The Polytechnic, Ibadan	
Senior Secondary Certificate Examination (SSCE)	2009 - 2015
Lord's College Ultimate Pride Academy	
First Leaving School Certificate	2000 - 2009
Goodness Royal School	